听力原文：聊城市二零二二年初中学生学业水平考试。第一节，听下面十个小对话，每个对话后面有一个小题。从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。听完每个对话后，你。都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每个对话仅读一遍。
Number 2 I want to be an engineer in the future.
What about you and your brother, Peter?
I want to be a scientist and my brother wants to be a policeman.
I want to be an engineer in the future.
What about you and your brother, Peter?
I want to be a scientist and my brother wants to be a policeman.
Number 3 It's raining hard outside.
It's a pity that we can't go out to play.
It's worry, the weather report says it'll be sunny this afternoon.
It's raining hard outside.
It's a pity that we can't go out to play.
Don't worry, the weather report says it'll be sunny this afternoon.
It's raining hard It's pity that we weather the It's It's a
It's raining it'll afternoon.
It's weather it'll go raining outside.
It's can't out play.
Don't the weather says it'll be afternoon.
It's the weather raining pity we
Don't Don't Don't worry, weather It's outside.
afternoon. Don't the weather play.
Don't the raining It's a
the Don't worry, weather weather Don't Don't worry, the play.
Don't worry, the Don't worry, weather it'll afternoon.
afternoon. Don't I want you to take out the rubbish, then clean the kitchen floor,
okay? Sure. Are grandma and grandpa coming?
Sure. Sure. grandma coming?
Sure. grandma grandpa coming?
coming? Sure. grandma grandma
Sure. grandma and coming?
grandma Sure. grandma
第二节，听下面四段对话，每段对话后各有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳。选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。听每段对话前，你有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话读两遍。听下面一段。对话，回答第十一至十三题。
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至十七题。
听下面一段对话，回答第十八至二十一题。
How long have you been in Beijing,
For two years.
I came here with my parents two years ago.
What do your parents do?
Oh, they are both teachers at a school in Beijing.
I see. How many friends have you made since you came here?
More than ten, I think.
Really? Who is your best friend?
Wang Wang Ning?
What does he look like?
He is tall, and he likes playing football and collecting stamps.
How did you make friends with him?
It was the early spring of my first year at a new school in Beijing.
No one knew me, and I was very lonely.
Then one day, Wang Ning gave you a smile?
Yes, that's right.
That smile made us become friends, and that smile also changed my life.
That smile smile smile changed right.
He is tall, and he likes playing football and collecting stamps.
How did you make friends with him?
It was the early spring of my first year at a new school in Beijing.
No one knew me, and I was very lonely.
Then one day, Wang Ning gave you a smile?
Yes, that's right.
That smile made us become friends, and that smile also changed my life.
I started to talk with other students.
听下面一段对话，回答。答第二十二至二十五题。
How did make my year year lonely.
It was Not yet.
How large is it?
About 1,428 square kilometers.
It is a magic land of mountains, forests, and rivers.
What is it famous for?
It's famous for its clean water and the strange shape of its tall rocks.
What did you do there?
I went along the Lijiang River by boat and enjoyed the beautiful sights.
I took a lot of photos, and I'll show them to you after I go back home.
Really? Thank you.
How soon will you be back home?
In three days.
Okay. See you then.
Have a good trip.
Thank you. See you then.
Hello, is that Amy?
Hello, this is Amy.
Who's calling, please?
This is Henry speaking.
Where are you at the moment?
Oh, at the moment, I'm in Yangshuo, Guilin, Guangxi.
In Yangshuo, where is it?
It's about 65 kilometers from here to the city center of Guilin.
Have you ever been here?
Not yet. How large is it?
About 1,428 square kilometers.
It is a magic land of mountains, forests, and rivers.
What is it famous for?
It's famous for its clean water and the strange shape of its tall rocks.
What did you do there?
I went along the Lijiang River by boat and enjoyed the beautiful sights.
I took a lot of and I'll show them to you after I go back home.
Really? Thank you.
How soon will you be back home?
In three days.
Okay. See you then.
Have a good trip.
Thank you. See you then.
第三节，听下面一段独白。独白后有五个小题，从题中所给的
B, and Chapter 4 Lao Shou was born in Beijing in 1899.
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。听独白前。你有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，每小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。该段独白读两遍。
His mother sent him to a teacher school in 1913.
After finishing school in 1918, he became a head teacher of a primary school.
In 1924, Lao Shou left home and went to England.
He taught Chinese at a college in London and returned to China five years later.
He wrote many plays, novels, and short stories about people's lives.
Tea House is one of Shou's most famous plays.
He wrote it in 1957, and it had three acts.
It tells us the story of Wang and the customers of his tea house in Beijing.
It describes the changes in Chinese society over 50 years.
Lao Shou was born in Beijing in 1899.
His mother sent him to a teacher school in 1913.
After finishing school in 1918, he became a head teacher of a primary school.
In 1924, Lao left home and went to England.
He taught Chinese at a college in London and returned to China five years later.
He wrote many plays, novels, and short stories about people's lives.
Tea House is one of Lao Shou's most famous plays.
He wrote it in 1957, and it has three acts.
It tells us the story of Wang and the customers of his tea house in Beijing.
It Thank
它描述了中国社会在50年中的变化。听力测试结束，请关注“锦鲤英语”微信公众号